{
  "q1": [
    {
      "question": "Brigade 2506 was a military group trained by this organization in an attempt to bring the Democratic RevolutionaryFronttopowerinonecountry.A1947NationalSecurityActcreatedthisorganizationwhich was preceded by the Office of Strategic Services. The Bay of Pigs Invasion, as well as several attempts to assassinate Castro, was planned by, for ten points, what federal agency responsible for gathering overseas intelligence?",
      "answer": [
        "CIA",
        "Central Intelligence Agency"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Louis XV demanded that this monarch renounce Francis I’s claims to the Duchy of Lorraine in favor of the deposed Stanislaw I of Poland. In the Treaty of Aachen, this monarch was forced to cede Parma to Bourbon Spain. This daughter of Charles VI fought a war with Frederick II which resulted in Prussia seizing control of Silesia. The Pragmatic Sanction of 1713 allowed the ascension of, for ten points, what Empress of Austria?",
      "answer": "Empress Maria Theresa"
    },
    {
      "question": "In 1957, Philip Siekevitz popularized a teaching tool regarding this organelle. This organelle names a theorized “Eve” figure who lived 150 thousand years ago; that figure is the matrilineal ancestor of all modern humans, because this organelle contains DNA typically only inherited from the mother. The Krebs cycle takes place in, for ten points, what organelle that generates ATP and is commonly called the powerhouse of the cell?",
      "answer": [
        "mitochondria",
        "mitochondrion"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "This leader initiated a series of economic reforms as part of Operation Forward. A mass sterilization campaign was carried out by this leader during the 21-month long Emergency. The Smiling Buddha test was authorized by this leader who ordered a raid on the Golden Temple in Amritsar in Operation Blue Star. Two Sikh bodyguards assassinated, for ten points, what Indian Prime Minister, the daughter of Jawaharlal Nehru?",
      "answer": "Indira Gandhi"
    },
    {
      "question": "Religious leaders criticized this man for holding Hugo Chavez’s mother at his funeral. This man, who has used his Twitter to support the University of Michigan football program and lament the death of rapper Nipsey Hussle, sought to develop a peaceful nuclear program in 2007 despite opposition from Ali Khamenei. Hassan Rouhani succeeded, for ten points, what former mayor of Tehran who served from 2005 to 2013 as President of Iran?",
      "answer": "Mahmoud Ahmadinejad"
    },
    {
      "question": "This man will supposedly fight both the al-Masih ad-Dajjal and his followers while dressed in yellow garb near Damascus. According to Al-Tabari, this man healed the son of Phillip the Tetrarch and created birds from clay to entertain children. Several Hadith testimonials and the Quran claim that this man was a product of a virgin birth. For ten points, name this penultimate prophet of Islam and son of Maryam who is considered the Messiah of the Old Testament.",
      "answer": [
        "Isa ibn Maryam",
        "Jesus Christ"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "This document’s predecessor was revised by the Annapolis Convention. An issue during the drafting of this document was resolved by the Connecticut Compromise. The beginning of this document promises to “Promote the general welfare” and “Insure Domestic Tranquility.” Edmund Randolph and George Mason refused to sign this document until the introduction of a Bill of Rights. For ten points, name this document, largely written by James Madison, the foundational document of the United States.",
      "answer": "United States” Constitution"
    },
    {
      "question": "One example of this musical form was inspired by a cat walking on a harpsichord and was composed by Domenico Scarlatti. Fourteen of these pieces in D minor are labeled “Contrapunctus” in a work titled for The Art of [these pieces]. Renaissance music theorist Gioseffo Zarlino contrasted these works and canons in the 16th century. J.S. Bach wrote a D minor organ piece that pairs one of these works with a “Toccata.” For ten points, name this type of contrapuntal work that is often paired with a prelude.",
      "answer": "fugues"
    },
    {
      "question": "This leader tasked Lot Smith to form a militia and eliminate the Timpanogos. The proposed state of “Deseret” was spearheaded by this man, who lost much of his national credibility following the Mountain Meadows Massacre. This leader banned black men in his clergy, claiming they were sons of Cain. This man took control of a religious group after its founder died in Illinois. The Mormons were led to Utah by, for ten points, what successor of Joseph Smith?",
      "answer": "Brigham Young"
    },
    {
      "question": "This man ordered that the coastal village of Tercanabal on the Sangres Peninsula be repopulated so that he could build a villa there. In order to search Africa for Prester John, this man convinced his father to conquer Ceuta in 1415. An expedition led by Gil Eannes, supported by this man, crossed Cape Bojador. For ten points, name this 15th century Portuguese prince whose funding helped start the Age of Discovery.",
      "answer": "Prince Henry the Navigator"
    }
  ],
  "q2": [
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This colony developed after civilians rejected a 1923 referendum to become the fifth province of South Africa. Leaders of this colony decided to ally with Antonio Salazar to resist the policy of “no independence before majority rule.” This colony issued the Unilateral Declaration of Independence under Ian Smith, sparking a civil war. The Lancaster House Agreement ended the Bush War in, for ten points, what British colony that became Zimbabwe?",
        "answer": "Rhodesia"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "The namesake of Rhodesia, Cecil Rhodes, planned an epic railway to connect these two African cities.",
        "answer": "Cape Town, South Africa and Cairo, Egypt"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "A.P Hall was forced to withdrawal from this battle due to a bout of pericarditis. John Bell Hood lost the use of his left arm due to injuries sustained during this battle. Despite being advised against it by James Longstreet, 12,000 soldiers crossed Cemetery Ridge in this battle in a charge led by George Pickett. George Meade led Union forces in, for ten points, what 1863 defeat for Robert E. Lee in Pennsylvania, the turning point of the Civil War?",
        "answer": "Battle of Gettysburg"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "In the aftermath of Gettysburg, Lee was forced to carry out a 2-week long retreat back to this state, eventually reaching safety after crossing the Potomac.",
        "answer": "Virginia"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This government was opposed by the Organisation Consul, which was formed by participants in the failed Kapp Putsch and members of the Freikorps. After an attack allegedly carried out by Marinus van der Lubbe, this government limited civil liberties with the Fire Decree. The constitution of this government was amended by the Enabling Act of 1933, in which Paul von Hindenburg granted his chancellor extreme political power. Massive hyperinflation afflicted, for ten points, what post-World War I German government?",
        "answer": "Weimar Republic"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Marinus van der Lubbe was accused of setting fire to this German parliament building in Berlin.",
        "answer": [
          "Reichstag",
          "Reichstagsgebaude"
        ]
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "During this event, a bannerman under En Hai assassinated German diplomat Clemens von Ketteler. In this conflict, foreign citizens were besieged for 55-days while taking refuge in the Legation Quarter. Sir Claude MacDonald commanded the Eight-Nation Alliance in response to this rebellion. During this rebellion, a provisional government was set-up in Tianjin to combat the Qing dynasty. The Righteous and Harmonious Fists launched, for ten points, what 1898 uprising against Western colonialism in China?",
        "answer": "Boxer Rebellion"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "The Boxer Rebellion was praised by this man, the founding father of the Republic of China.",
        "answer": "Sun Yat-Sen"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "Charlie Siringo worked undercover in this specific industry to bust an 1892 labor strike in Coeur d’Alene. The Washoe and Reese River processes extracted this good. Official U.S reliance on this good was ended by the “Crime of “73.” Mount Davidson in Nevada was the site of an 1859 rush to the Comstock Lode, a massive find of this resource. For ten points, name this precious metal that could be exchanged at a fixed rate with a more precious metal in bimetallism.",
        "answer": "silver"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "U.S. gold and silver coins were known by this specific term, referencing money in the form of coins and not notes. A “Circular” named for this term was passed in 1836 by Andrew Jackson.",
        "answer": [
          "specie",
          "Specie Circular"
        ]
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "The first Christian Mass in the Philippines was led by this explorer who was later ostracized after a falling out with King Manuel. This man died in a skirmish with the Lapu-Lapu on the island of Mactan. This explorer navigated a strait south of Chile during a lengthy expedition he led from the La Trinidad. For ten points, name this Portuguese sailor who led the first successful circumnavigation of the world.",
        "answer": "Ferdinand Magellan"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Magellan fell out of favor with King Manuel after poor performance in a campaign against this nearby kingdom, once ruled by the Almohad dynasty.",
        "answer": "Morocco"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "In one book, this philosopher argued that impressions and ideas were only different in terms of degree. The works of this philosopher awoke Immanuel Kant from his “dogmatic slumber.” This philosopher, who made the “is-ought” distinction and posited a missing shade of blue, wrote Dialogues Concerning Natural Religion and A Treatise of Human Nature. For ten points, name this Scottish empiricist, the author of An Enquiry Concerning Human Understanding.",
        "answer": "David Hume"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Hume wrote a lauded six-volume History of England, which he began writing during a 1745 uprising of this movement, which sought to restore the House of Stuart to the throne. This movement effectively ended after the Battle of Culloden.",
        "answer": [
          "Jacobites",
          "word forms relating to Jacobitism"
        ]
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "In two novels by this author, Sweetness shuns her daughter for her dark skin, and Milkman Dead comes of age amidst twentieth-century racial turmoil. This author of God Help the Child and Song of Solomon wrote about Pecola Breedlove’s obsessive desire to look like a white girl, and described Sethe’s fear of the daughter she killed to save her from slavery. For ten points, name this American author of The Bluest Eye and Beloved, who passed away in August 2019.",
        "answer": [
          "Toni Morrison",
          "Chloe Anthony Wofford Morrison",
          "Chloe Ardelia Wofford"
        ]
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Toni Morrison is the most recent American novelist to receive this international literary prize, which she was awarded in 1993. Bob Dylan was controversially awarded this prize in 2016, on the basis that his lyrics were poetic.",
        "answer": "Nobel Prize in Literature"
      }
    }
  ],
  "q3": [
    {
      "category": "Supreme Court Justices",
      "prompt": "Name the US Supreme Court justice who...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Became the first woman on the Court after being appointed by Ronald Reagan.",
          "answer": "Sandra Day O’Connor"
        },
        {
          "question": "Died in 2016, creating a vacancy filled by Neil Gorsuch.",
          "answer": "Antonin Scalia"
        },
        {
          "question": "Headed the commission that investigated the assassination of John F. Kennedy.",
          "answer": "Earl Warren"
        },
        {
          "question": "Outlined the “clear and present danger” doctrine in Schenck v United States",
          "answer": "Oliver Wendell Holmes Jr."
        },
        {
          "question": "Refused to retire in 2018 despite being diagnosed with cancer.",
          "answer": "Ruth Bader Ginsburg"
        },
        {
          "question": "Was the first Chief Justice.",
          "answer": "John Jay"
        },
        {
          "question": "Ruled that Dred Scott was not a free man in a majority opinion for an 1857 case.",
          "answer": "Roger Taney"
        },
        {
          "question": "Wrote a memo defending the “separate-but-equal” doctrine while a clerk under Robert Jackson.",
          "answer": "William Rehnquist"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "category": "Turkey",
      "prompt": "Name the...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Empire that it succeeded after World War I.",
          "answer": "Ottoman Empire"
        },
        {
          "question": "Most populous city in Turkey, the site of a failed 2016 coup.",
          "answer": "Istanbul"
        },
        {
          "question": "Felt, usually red, headdress named for a Moroccan city that was banned in 1925.",
          "answer": "fez"
        },
        {
          "question": "Capital, which was used as the base for the National Assembly during the Turkish War of Interdependence.",
          "answer": "Ankara"
        },
        {
          "question": "Founding father of Turkey, who became its first President of 1923.",
          "answer": [
            "Mustafa Kemal Ataturk",
            "either",
            "both names"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "Ethnic cleansing carried out by Turkey in the early 20th century.",
          "answer": "Armenian Genocide"
        },
        {
          "question": "Country that entered into “Earthquake Diplomacy” with Turkey.",
          "answer": "Greece"
        },
        {
          "question": "1923 treaty that created Turkey, following the failed Treaty of S`evres.",
          "answer": "Treaty of Lausanne"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "category": "Samurai",
      "prompt": "Name the...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Country where they served nobility for centuries.",
          "answer": [
            "Japan",
            "Nippon",
            "Nihon"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "General name for the curved sword they wielded.",
          "answer": "katana"
        },
        {
          "question": "Feudal land-owners served by samurai; they served the shogun.",
          "answer": "daimyo"
        },
        {
          "question": "Code of honor by which they lived.",
          "answer": "bushido"
        },
        {
          "question": "Form of ritual disembowelment they employed to honorably kill themselves.",
          "answer": [
            "seppuku",
            "harakiri"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "Term for a samurai without a master.",
          "answer": "ronin"
        },
        {
          "question": "Intricate ceremony they performed that takes place at chashitsu and involves thick and thin variants of a substance.",
          "answer": [
            "tea ceremony",
            "chanoyu",
            "sado",
            "chado"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "Legendary samurai who wrote The Book of Five Rings.",
          "answer": [
            "Miyamoto Musashi",
            "Shinmen Takezo",
            "Miyamoto Bennosuke",
            "Ninten Doraku"
          ]
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  "q4": [
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) After losing the Battle of Stilo, a king of this name faced a rebellion called the Great Slav Uprising led by the Wendish people. With Conrad the Red, a king of this name ended the Magyar invasion of Bavaria by the chieftain (20 pts)",
        "Bulcsu [BULL-choo] at a 955 battle. That king with this name agreed to be the secular protector of the Holy See, starting the (10 pts)",
        "Holy Roman Empire. For ten points, give this name of a “Great” German king who was the son of Henry the Fowler and who defeated the Hungarians at Lechfeld."
      ],
      "answer": [
        "Otto",
        "Otto the Great",
        "Otto I, II, and/or III"
      ]
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) To promote the London Underground, Horace Taylor created a poster of commuters on escalators in this artistic style. Hidden bars with mirror-topped tables were created in this style to conceal liquor during Prohibition. A street named for Benjamin Franklin is home to one of the earliest (20 pts)",
        "buildings in this style created by Henri Sauvage in Paris. Another building designed in this style was decorated with radiator caps and gargoyles and, upon completion in (10 pts)",
        "1931, surpassed the Empire State Building as the tallest building in the world. The Chrysler Building exemplifies, for ten points, what highly modern style that flourished in the 1920s?"
      ],
      "answer": "Art Deco"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This man’s wife organized private lectures with William Thackeray and Charles Dickens after creating the White House library. While trying to run for a 2nd term, this man lost the (20 pts)",
        "Whig nomination to Winfield Scott. This President ordered Matthew Perry to open up (10 pts)",
        "Japan to western trade. In the Election of 1856, this man ran on the Know Nothing ticket but was soundly defeated by John C. Fremont and James Buchanan. For ten points, name this President who succeeded Zachary Taylor in 1850."
      ],
      "answer": "Millard Fillmore"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This conflict prompted CIA chief John Stockwell to resign after foreign troops invaded Shaba. A minor player in this conflict was the FLEC, a front for the liberation of Cabinda. This conflict became known as (20 pts)",
        "“Cuba’s Vietnam” after the amount of aid that Fidel Castro sent to aid Agostinho Neto. This war finally ended when Jonas Savimbi was killed in (10 pts)",
        "2002, ending 27 years of fighting that began when Portugal granted the country independence. The UNITA and MPLA factions fought in, for ten points, what civil war in southern Africa?"
      ],
      "answer": "Angolan Civil War"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This activity was banned at the Russian Antarctic stations in 1959 after a frustrated scientist killed his opponent with an ax. Both Napoleon and Benjamin Franklin were beaten by “The Turk,” a (20 pts)",
        "hoax automaton that played this game. Komodo and Stockfish are modern computer programs that improved on the AI system (10 pts)",
        "Deep Blue, which defeated Garry Kasparov at this game in 1997. Magnus Carlsen is the current world champion of, for ten points, what centuries-old board game involving knights and rooks?"
      ],
      "answer": "chess"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) Fighting at this location prompted Operation Moolah, an attempt by one side to purchase the other’s weaponry. Heroes like Frederick Blesse and Joseph McConnell emerged from fighting in this location. Both the Gloster Meteor and (20 pts)",
        "P51-Mustang were replaced by the US Air Force to better control this location, which is found where the (10 pts)",
        "Yalu River enters the Yellow Sea, The F-86 Sabre dueled a namesake Soviet aircraft in, for ten points, what “alley,” a hotspot for dogfighting jets in the Korean War?"
      ],
      "answer": "MiG Alley"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) In this country, a resistance cell led by Missak Manounchian was executed by the Secret Field Police. Josephine (20 pts)",
        "Baker smuggled coded messages to this country from England by hiding them on her sheet music. An organization in this country that adopted the (10 pts)",
        "Lorraine Cross as their symbol sabotaged utilities and telecommunication networks in preparation for the Allied invasion of Normandy. For ten points, name this country where resistance cells fought Nazi occupation of cities like Paris."
      ],
      "answer": "France"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This city’s racist housing covenants were the subject of Shelley v. Kraemer. The Pruitt-Igoe housing projects were built in this city, which is home to an early terra cotta skyscraper designed by Adler and (20 pts)",
        "Sullivan. An Eero Saarinen-designed inverted catenary commemorates the beginning of the (10 pts)",
        "Lewis and Clark Expedition, which departed from this city. The Wainwright Building was built in, for ten points, what city on the Mississippi River, the home of the Gateway Arch?"
      ],
      "answer": "St. Louis"
    }
  ]
}